# Khushkaran Bajwa

Derby, United Kingdom http://khushkaran.com

#### **About Me**

I am a software engineer with several years of experience in developing web apps and mobile applications. Development is much more than writing code, a developer should be able to cover the breakdown of a problem through to the deployment of the solution. I subscribe to the Software Craftsmanship Manifesto, passionate about Agile Development, BDD and am always looking for avenues to professionally and personally advance myself.

**Technical Skills** 

Like:

ruby, ruby-on-rails, elixir, git, angularjs, redis, reactjs, php

## **Experience**

## **Developer** - Causeway Technologies

August 2014 - Current

ruby ruby-on-rails jquery angularjs reactjs elixir bdd

Developing a distributed app platform based on Ruby on Rails with an AngularJS front end and ReactJS apps. Also developed an Elixir API with the Phoenix web framework to provide User Details to the apps within the platform.

Mocha, Chai, Sinon and Karma were used to test the Javascript, whilst RSpec was used for acceptance testing of the API. Cucumber was used for end-to-end testing.

Developer - Kesri Nishaan

2011 - 2014

objective-c html5 css php javascript jquery

Developed an iOS app that stored files offline for reading at a later point, another app allowed the playback of streamed media. A PHP service was developed to interact with the APNS to deliver push notifications to the apps.

Cocos2D was also used to develop a great game that worked across iPhones, iPads and Macs.

#### **Education**

#### **Developer Bootcamp**

2014 - 2014

For my final project, I worked on SL8, an app that allowed students to request the attention of tutors by asking questions. This was to replace students having to write their name on the whiteboard. The tutor then would work their way around to them, and mark off the answers through the mobile site. If the list grew too long, using Twilio, it would send an SMS to the teach to inform them. All code was tested using RSpec and Capybara.

## **BA (Hons) Accounting & Finance**

2008 - 2011

Developed an iOS app that allowed the simple calculation of company statements as a hobby.

## Projects

#### GitHub - baanis

github.com/khushkaran/baanis June 2015

Baanis in CSV format with Transliteration and Translation

GitHub - slate

github.com/khushkaran/slate

Final Project @makersacademy - a waiting list and stats for students/teachers

May 2014

